<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://edimah.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://edimah.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-09-27T02:54:32+00:00</updated><id>https://edimah.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A personal website combining my projects, and bits and pieces to share my understanding of many fields. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Importing and visualising Apple Health data with R</title><link href="https://edimah.github.io/blog/2025/importing-and-visualising-fitness-data/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Importing and visualising Apple Health data with R"/><published>2025-09-26T22:34:16+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-26T22:34:16+00:00</updated><id>https://edimah.github.io/blog/2025/importing-and-visualising-fitness-data</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://edimah.github.io/blog/2025/importing-and-visualising-fitness-data/"><![CDATA[<p>I have been using my iPhone and Apple Watch’s health features consistently for almost two years now.</p> <p>For <strong>twenty months</strong> to be exact.</p> <p>I had always wondered what insights I could extract from that data, and how I could adjust my training accordingly. No time like the present: I imported and parsed my personal health data and decided to play around with it.</p> <iframe src="/assets/html/workout_types_20250926_221543.html" width="100%" height="600" frameborder="0"></iframe> <p>Starting with a <strong>bar plot</strong> showing the distributions of my physical activities, using parts of my final dataset. Hovering over each bar should show counts for each workout type !</p> <p>Though this graph doesn’t say much about trends and performances, I’m surprised to see which activity actually dominates my routine 🧘🏿‍♀️. I guess doing short flows consistently before and after other workouts tends to add up !</p> <p>Looks like I could benefit from going outside more, though. Unless plotting my workout data against time shows unexpected trends…</p> <p><em>TBC.</em></p> <p>This quick visual is the first in a series of short posts exploring my own Apple Health metrics through a holistic lense: descriptive, inferential and predictive statistics.</p> <p>For anyone interested, a lightweight version of my script is available in my <a href="https://github.com/Edimah/apple-health-data"><strong>Apple Health Data</strong> GitHub repo</a>. Feel free to use it !</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="dataviz"/><category term="fitness"/><category term="health"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I imported and visualised 20 months of Apple Health data 🏃🏿‍♀️ to get a broader view of how I trained.]]></summary></entry></feed>